Inventory of the Barnes Family Papers 1797-1926, 1818-1875
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Correspondence, n.d., 57 items. ALS. (Box-folder 3:154-210)
  - J[udy] L. Sydnor, n.p., to "Willy" [Newman] Williamson [B.] Barnes, Richmond, [Virginia], n.d., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:200)
    Re: request for 'shoes to be made; surprised that NWBB did not see more of "the girls" while they were in Richmond.
  - J[udy] L. S[ydnor], n.p., to "Willy" [Newman] Williamson [B.] Barnes, Richmond, [Virginia], n.d., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:201)
    Re: news of JLS's poor health.
    Also includes a letter by Margaret [W. Tomlin?], n.p., to "Willy" [Newman] Williamson [B.] Barnes, Richmond, [Virginia]. Re: request for cloth.
  - H[arrison] B. Tomlin, University of Virginia, [Charlottesville], [Virginia], to Margaret W. [Tomlin] Barnes, Jeffersonton P.O., Culpepper C[oun]ty, Virginia, 15 Dec. n.y., 1 page. ALS. Incomplete. (Box-folder 3:202)
    Re: Christmas holidays - the visitors require the professors to lecture over the holidays and HBT must not miss any, therefore, he cannot spend Christmas with Margaret and brother Willy.
  - Judy H. Tomlin, Retreat, [Virginia], to "Willy" [Newman] Williamson [B.] Barnes, Richmond, [Virginia], 29 Sept. n.y., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:203)
    Re: circumstances surrounding the death of Sally and her mother's intense grief; Margaret is quite sick but the rest here are well.
  - Judy H. Tomlin, n.p., to "Willy" [Newman] Williamson [B.] Barnes, Richmond, [Virginia], n.d., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:204)
    Re: request for yard goods from Richmond; JHT looks forward to Willy's visit.
  - Margaret Tomlin, Stanley, [Virginia], to "Aunt Margaret" Margaret W. [Tomlin] Barnes, Falmouth, Stafford County, Virginia, 26 Oct. n.y., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:205)
    Re: requests extension of visiting period for "Peg"; news of Aunt Mary's health.
    Also includes a letter by [Margaret] [W.] [Barnes], Stanley, [Virginia], to "Mama" [Margaret] W. [Tomlin] Barnes, Falmouth, Stafford County, Virginia Re: request for MWTB to send some clothing for MWB's extended visit.
  - Margaret W. Tomlin, Hanover, [Virginia], to "Willy" [Newman] [Williamson] [B.] [Barnes], n.p., n.d., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:206)
    Re: MWT has been ill; MWT will remain in Hanover one or two more weeks.
  - Margaret [W.] Tomlin, n.p., to "Willy" [Newman] Williamson [B.] Barnes, Hanover Town, [Virginia], n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 3:207)
    Re: yard goods requested.
  - [?], n.p., to [?] Barnes & [?] Tomlin, n.p., n.d., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:208)
    Re: please send silk dress and fabric.
    Also includes a note by [?J, n.p., to [?] Barnes [?] Tomlin, n.p. Re: Jannet sent Bal[sora]something in a vial to rub her foot with.
  - "Aunt Hess" [?], n.p., to "Peggy" [Margaret] [W.] Barnes, C[heri]coke, [Virginia], n.d., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:209)
    Re: death of Mrs. B_ and circumstances surrounding situations; my baby seems poorly and so nervous; much obliged to MWB for your kind sympathy and affection; love to one and all.
  - [?], n.p., to [?], n.p., n.d., 2 pages. AL. Incomplete. (Box-folder 3:210)
    Also includes a letter by [Margaret] [W.] [Barnes], n.p., to "Mama" [Margaret] [W.] [Tomlin] [Barnes], n.p.
    Also includes a letter by B[everley] D. Barnes, n.p., to [?], n.p.
  Series 6: Envelopes
- Envelopes., 19 items. (Box-folder 3:211)
  Series 7: Financial Papers
- Financial Papers, 1844-1855., 9 items. ALS. (Box-folder 3:212)
  - List of expenses for Mr. N. W. Barnes, 1844-1848., 1 page. (Box-folder 3:212)
  - Receipt for a pair of shoes purchased by Margaret Barnes, 6 Nov. 1852., 1 page. (Box-folder 3:212)
  - Receipt, 4 July 18[53]., 1 page. (Box-folder 3:212)
  - Receipt/Bill for items purchased by Mrs. W. M. Barnes from T. H. Kellogg, 12 Dec. 1853-20 March 1860., 1 page. (Box-folder 3:212)
  - Receipt/Bill for a china pitcher purchased by Mrs. M. Williamson Barnes from T. H. Kellogg, 20 March 1854-1 July 1836., 1 page. (Box-folder 3:212)
  - Receipt for an item purchased by [Mr.] N. W. Barnes, 20 March 1854., 1 page. (Box-folder 3:212)
  - Receipt for a bushel of seed purchased by Mr. Barnes from Wellford, Eastham and Co., 16 Aug. 1854., 1 page. (Box-folder 3:212)
  - Receipt/Bill for an items purchased by Mr. N. W. Barnes, 1854-1855., 1 page. (Box-folder 3:212)
  - Receipt/Bill for item(s) purchased by Mr. N. W. Barnes, 9 April 1855., 1 page. (Box-folder 3:212)
  Series 8: Newspaper Clippings
- Newspaper Clippings, 1927, 2 items. ALS. (Box-folder 3:213)
  - Lynchburg News, 22 Feb. 1827. (Box-folder 3:213)
    Re: Ditchley.
  - Lynchburg News, 1927. (Box-folder 3:213)
    Re: Christ Church.
  Series 9: Poetry
- Poetry, 1847-1858., 2 items. ALS. (Box-folder 3:214)
  - Two poems written by Margaret Barnes, 1847., 2 page. (Box-folder 3:214)
    First poem is entitled "A Royal Colloguing"[sp?]. The second poem, begun after the completion of the first, is only a few lines, thus most likely incomplete.
  - Two poems written by Walker Barnes from Pine Wood, near Falmouth, Virginia, Nov. 1858., 4 pages. (Box-folder 3:214)
- Recipe for salve, n.d., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:215)